Guide to the Civil War Photograph File 1861-1865, [1880-1889] PR 164
New-York Historical Society
Civil War photograph file
1861-1865, [1880-1889]
New-York Historical Society
PR 164
12.55 Linear feet (11 boxes)
Photographs taken of and during the United States Civil War. Photographs show battle scenes, camps, soliders, officers, and war-related paraphernalia. Some photographs were taken during the war and published afterward.
Access Restrictions
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Major donors to the Civil War Photograph File include Daniel Parish (ca. 1841-1914) who gave massive amounts of Civil War material to the Historical Society over many years. Other gifts came from Henry O. Havemeyer (1961), and O.E Havemeyer (1962).
Arrangement
The collection is organized in nine series:
Series I. War Scenes and Sites
Series II. Portraits
Series III. Havemeyer Collection
Series IV. "Incidents of the War"
Series V. "Brady's Album Gallery"
Series VI. Plates from Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the War
Series VII. Naval Scenes and Sites
Series VIII. Relief Organizations
Series IX. Later Platinum Prints
Related Materials
Thousands of photographic images of the Civil War can be found in the Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections's War of the Rebellion Photograph Albums (PR 88) and Stereograph File (PR 65). Hundreds of portraits of war participants can be found in the Carte de Visite File (PR 11), Cased Photograph File (PR 12), Portrait File (PR 52), Mathew B. Brady Studio Portrait Photograph Collection (PR 85), and the Imperial Portrait Photograph File (PR 210).
Scope and Contents
The Civil War Photograph File spans the full period of the War of the Rebellion, 1861-1865. It contains photographs in various formats and generations relating to the conflict and the men and women involved. Though all of the prints may not have been made during the war period, they are from period negatives made either in the field or photographer's studio; therefore, there are no memorial scenes or soldier reunions included in the collection.
In many cases there may be variant "states" of a single image found in different series. For example, the collection holds four copies of Alexander Gardner's portrait of the Fairfax Court House. There is one print in the "Incidents of the War" series, one copy in the plates from Gardner's Sketchbook, and two as albumen prints received as unmounted prints (one from Parish's 1906 gift) and mounted on card stock by the N-YHS bindery (filed in Series I.)
Albumen prints.; Cartes-de-visite (card photographs); Platinum prints.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Battlefields.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Destruction and pillage.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Military life.; Fort Pulaski (Ga.); Fort Sumter (Charleston, S.C.); Armies -- Officers.; Andersonville Prison; Brady, Mathew B., approximately 1823-1896; Burnside, Ambrose Everett, 1824-1881 -- Portraits; Gardner, Alexander, 1821-1882; Haas, Philip, active 1837-1863; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865 -- Portraits; Meade, George Gordon, 1815-1872 -- Portraits; Moore, Henry P., 1833-1911; O'Sullivan, Timothy H., 1840-1882
- Series I: War Scenes and Sites
  Scope and Contents note
  Series I. War Scenes and Sites contains views of battlefields, forts, and other places associated with war battles or events. About half of the images also show soldiers or other people; the rest are desolate empty scenes. The series includes three composite panorama photographs: a view of Gettysburg from Seminary Ridge; the Army of the Potomac at Cumberland Landing, Pamunkey, VA, May 1862; and a view of the Camp of the 40th Massachusetts Infantry at Miners Hill, VA.
  Several photographs by New Hampshire photographer Henry P. Moore (1835-1911) can be found filed with views of South Carolina and Georgia. Moore took pictures of the locations where New Hampshire regiments were stationed in the 1862-1863 period. Moore's prints have a blue paper label affixed to the lower right of their mounts, though Moore's name has been cut from the label itself. Other photographs by Moore include views of the USS Wabash, marked and unmarked.
  There are two sets (seven of nine numbered images) of card-mounted photographs taken at Fort Pulaski, Georgia, which are signed in the negative "Lt. P. Haas." Philip Haas was a second lieutenant in the 1st New York Engineers regiment who had worked as a daguerreotypist in New York City before enlisting. Lt. Haas appears to have taken on a partner at some point, and produced prints on mounts marked "Photo by Haas & Peale Morris Island & Hilton Head S.C.," and signed in the negative, "Haas & Peale." This collection holds five images (nos. 8, 12, 13, 17, and 32) from a series of photographs taken by the partners on the islands off South Carolina. The "South Carolina Morris Island" folder contains four images by Haas & Peale of buildings and installations, as well as one photograph of the "Swamp Angel."
  This series also holds seven out of a set of eight photographs of the prisoner of war camp at Andersonville, Georgia, made in 1864 by Confederate photographer A. J. Riddle. They were issued on letterpress mount with descriptive captions.
  The only view of Baltimore is one small photograph of the front gate of Fort McHenry showing a portion of the hospital.
  One important set of photographs is thirteen views of Forts Sumter and Moultrie in Charleston Harbor, the work of an unidentified photographer. Each mount is labeled with a full description of the image and features an autographed approval note by the victorious Confederate Brigadier General Pierre T. Beaureguard (1818-1893). The photographs were made on April 15 and 16, 1861, just after the evacuation of the defeated Union forces. Many more images of both of these South Carolina forts can be found in Series V, "Brady's Album Gallery." A second set of three views of Fort Sumter are mammoth plate albumen prints mounted on letterpress sheets. Issued as commemoratives to be presented by Secretary of War Edwin M. Stanton to Major General John A. Dix (1798-1879) as a guest at the ceremonies of restoring the national flag on the fort on April 14, 1865, all three mounts are inscribed by Brigadier General Richard Delafield (1798-1873) who was then Chief Engineer of the Army Corps of Engineers.
  The "Tennessee" folder holds an image labeled the "Rebel Saltpeter Source, the Nicojack Cave" in Marion County near Chattanooga, by Morse, a Nashville photographer. Saltpeter was a major component of gunpowder and Tennessee was a major supplier of this important resource.
  Photographs of dead soldiers can be found filed in Sharpsburg, Petersburg, Fredricksburg, Chancellorsville, Richmond, Manassas, Gettysburg, Antietam, and Cold Harbor.
  Images are filed alphabetically by state.
  - District of Columbia
    - Washington, 1863, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - Georgia
    - Allatoona Pass, Atlanta, and Savannah, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    - Andersonville Prison, set of seven photographs by A. J. Riddle taken August 17, 1864, 1865d (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
    - Fort Pulaski, 1863, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - Fort Pulaski, two sets of photographs by Lt. Philip Haas, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - Tybee Island, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - Louisiana
    - Alexandra, 1864 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
  - Maryland
    - Antietam (Sharpsburg) and Baltimore--Casualties, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
    - Antietam (Sharpsburg) and Baltimore--General Views, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - New York
    - Fort Hamilton and Fort Lafayette, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
  - North Carolina
    - Fort Fisher, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
  - Pennsylvania
    - Gettysburg -- Casualties, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
    - Gettysburg -- Round Top, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
    - Gettysburg -- General Views, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
  - South Carolina
    - Edisto Island, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 15)
    - Folly Island, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 16)
    - Fort Sumter, 1865, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 17)
      General note
      See also: Box 11, Folder 103
    - Fort Sumter and Fort Moultrie, Beauregard set, 1861, Apr. 15-16 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 18)
    - Hilton Head, 1864, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 19)
    - Morris Island and Folly Island, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 20)
  - Tennessee
    - Miscellaneous views, including Chattanooga, Knoxville, Lookout Mountain, and Nashville, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 21)
  - Virginia
    - Alexandria, 1864 Jun 12, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 22)
    - Appomatox area, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 23)
    - Aquia Creek, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 24)
    - Belle Plain, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 25)
    - Brandy Station--Hospital, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 26)
    - Brandy Station--General Views, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 27)
    - Centreville, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 28)
    - Chancellorsville, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 29)
    - Charles City Courthouse, 1864 Jun (Offsite-box 3, Folder 30)
    - City Point, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 31)
    - Cold Harbor, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 32)
    - Cumberland Landing, 1862 May (Offsite-box 3, Folder 33)
    - Dutch Gap, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 34)
    - Fairfax area, 1861, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 35)
    - Falls Church, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 36)
    - Fort Brady, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 37)
    - Fredericksburg, 1863, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 38)
    - Gaines Mill, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 39)
    - Glendale (Fraser's Farm), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 40)
    - James River, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 41)
    - Jones Landing (Offsite-box 4, Folder 41)
      See: James River
    - Manassas--Bull Run Creek area, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 42)
    - Manassas--General views, including Manassas Junction, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 43)
    - Miners Hill, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 44)
    - Petersburg--Fort Sedgwick and Fort Steadman, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 45)
    - Petersburg--General views, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 46)
    - Port Walthall Junction (Cobb's Hill, Redoubt Zabriskie), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 47)
    - Potomac River scenes, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 48)
    - Richmond, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 49)
    - Seven Pines (Fair Oaks), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 50)
    - Yorktown, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 51)
    - Miscellaneous locations, including Jericho Mills on the North Anna River, and White House, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 52)
  - West Virginia
    - Harper's Ferry, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 53)
  - Unidentified Views
    - General views, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 54)
    - Special Equipment, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 55)
- Series II: Portraits
  Series II is arranged in three subseries: Composites, Groups, and Individuals. Thereunder, they are divided by portraits made in photographers' studios and those taken in the field. They are alphabetically arranged within those categories. There are many more portraits of Civil War participants in the Department's PR 011 Carte de Visite File, both filed alphabetically under the sitter's surname, and at the end of the collection in unidentified military portraits.
  - Composite
    - Cartes de visite of military officers and statesmen; collection of O.H. Oldroyd of Columbus, Ohio, 1866 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 104)
    - General Robert E. Lee and Staff by Rockwell and Cowell, 1866 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 104)
    - Soldiers' Fair in Springfield, MA, December 22, 1864, By J.C. Spooner, 1865 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 104)
  - Group (Field)
    - Keystone Independent Battery Light Artillery, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
    - 12th Regiment of New York Infantry, 1861 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 105)
    - 132nd Regiment of New York Infantry, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
    - "Council of War," painting showing generals Meade and Grant at Massaponax Church, photographed by Timothy O'Sullivan, 1964 May 21 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
    - Generals Robert Anderson and Ambrose Burnside, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
    - General Ambrose Burnside and his contraband, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
    - General Samuel W. Crawford and staff, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
    - General Robert S. Foster and staff, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
    - General Ulysses S. Grant and staff at Cold Harbor, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
    - General Samuel Heintzelman and staff, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
    - General George G. Meade and staff, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
    - General George G. Meade and corps commanders of the Army of the Potomac, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
    - General Alfred Pleasanton and staff, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
    - Admiral Porter and officers, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
    - General John Sedgwick and others, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
    - Major General Edwin V. Sumner and staff, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
    - General Unger and staff, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
    - Stanton Wells and others, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
    - Unidentified groups, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
  - Group (Studio)
    - General Ambrose B. Burnside and staff, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 106)
    - General Samuel W. Crawford and staff, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 106)
    - General Ulysses S. Grant and staff, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 106)
    - General Philip Sheridan and staff, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 57)
    - General William T. Sherman and staff, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 57)
    - Sergeants, 2nd New York Mounted Rifles, Company L, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 57)
    - Unidentified groups, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 57)
  - Groups with Abraham Lincoln
    - Groups with Abraham Lincoln, 1861-1862, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 58)
  - Individuals
    - Unidentified soldiers, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 59)
- Series III: Havemeyer Collection
  Series III holds prints donated to the New-York Historical Society by Henry Osborne Havemeyer (1876-1965) in September 1961. Havemeyer gave "78 photographs of the Civil War 1861-1864 in two canvas covers" which were mounted on taupe paperboards by the Society at a later date. The photographs are arranged in two subseries, Scenes and Portraits. Many of the images in this series also appear in Series I.
  Scenes are filed alphabetically by state. Portraits are filed by type and thereunder alphabetically by General.
  - Scenes
    - Pennsylvania--Gettysburg, undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 60)
    - South Carolina--Charleston, undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 61)
    - South Carolina--Port Royal, undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 62)
    - Virginia--Alexandria, undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 63)
    - Virginia--Bull Run, undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 64)
    - Virginia--Centreville, undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 65)
    - Virginia--City Point, undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 66)
    - Virginia--Deep Bottom, undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 67)
    - Virginia--Fort Brady, undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 68)
    - Virginia--Fredericksburg, undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 69)
    - Virginia--Manassas, undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 70)
    - Virginia--Petersburg, undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 71)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 72)
  - Portraits--Group
    - Regiments, undated (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - Generals and staff--Birney, Ambrose Burnside, Samuel W. Crawford, Edward Ferrero, Foster, undated (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - Generals and staff--David Gregg, Griffin, George Hartsuff, undated (Box 6, Folder 75)
    - Generals and staff--Rufus Ingalls, James Ledlie, John Martindale, undated (Box 6, Folder 76)
    - Generals and staff--Philip Sheridan, Edwin Sumner, Terry, Godfrey Weitzel, Orlando Willcox, undated (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Portraits--Individuals, undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 78)
- Series IV: "Incidents of the War"
  Series IV holds albumen prints by various photographers that were mounted on letterpress sheets for sale to the public. Published in series and distributed during the war, these prints are a good source for attribution as both the negative and photograph maker are credited. Many of the photographs are dated as well.
  At the end of the series is a single and odd image by W. Morris Smith of Washington, DC, a photograph of a composite photograph to which Smith had added a rather crudely painted foreground (signed and dated by him on a rock at the lower left).
  The series is arranged in four subseries by photographer-publisher: Brady; Gardner; Gardner Published by Philp and Solomons; and Smith. Thereunder they are filed alphabetically by image title.
  - Brady, Mathew B., Studio
    - 1st Rhode Island Reg., (Camp Sprague) [Burnside], 1861 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 79)
    - 22nd Reg., New York Infantry National Guard, 1862 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 80)
      One image in 3-3/8 x 3-7/8 inch format
    - 22nd Reg., New York Infantry National Guard, [1863] (Offsite-box 7, Folder 80)
      Five images in 6-1/2 x 8-3/4 inch format
  - Gardner, Alexander
    - Antietam Bridge, No. 1, September 1862 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 81)
    - Battery No. 4, Near Yorktown, May 1862, 1863 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 81)
    - Burnside Bridge, No. 1, September 1862 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 81)
    - Encampment at Manassas, March 1862 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 81)
    - Fairfax Court-House, 1863 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 81)
    - Fredericksburg, No. 2, 1863 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 81)
    - Gen. Burnside and Staff, Warrenton, November 1862 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 81)
    - General Post-Office, Army of the Potomac, Brandy Station, VA, December, 1863, 1865 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 81)
    - Group at Mrs. Lee's, near Birkittsville, MD, November 1, 1862 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 81)
    - Interior View of Breastworks on Round Top, Gettysburg, 1863 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 82)
    - Marshall House, Alexandria, VA, August, 1862, 1865 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 82)
    - Military Telegraphic Corps Army of the Potomac, Berlin, October 1862 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 82)
    - Quaker Guns, Centreville, March 1862 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 82)
    - Pontoon Bridge Across the Potomac, Berlin, October 1862 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 82)
    - Slave Pen, Alexandria, VA, August 1863, 1865 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 82)
    - Stone Church, Centreville, Used as a Hospital after the Battle of 18th July 1861, 1862 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 82)
    - Stone Church, Centreville, VA, March, 1862, 1865 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 82)
  - Gardner, Alexander, Published By Philp & Solomons.
    - Army Church built by 50th N.Y.V. Engineers at their Winter Camp in Front of Petersburg, [1864] (Offsite-box 7, Folder 83)
    - Dutch Gap Canal, Looking North, 2d April 1865 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 83)
    - Interior View of Traverse after Bombardment of Fort Fisher, NC, undated (Offsite-box 7, Folder 83)
    - Ruins of Arsenal, Richmond, undated (Offsite-box 7, Folder 83)
  - Smith, W. Morris
    - Signal Camp of Instruction, Georgetown, DC, 1865 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 84)
- Series V: "Brady's Album Gallery"
  Series V contains two types of small format photographs published by the Mathew Brady Studio. The albumen prints were mounted on card stock letterpress printed with copyright data, and with a paper label on the verso giving the image number and a description of the scene shown. The images were issued both in carte de visite (2-1/2 x 4 inches) and album (4-1/2 x 6 inches) size, as well as in stereograph format; they were meant for purchase by soldiers and the general public. The series holds comparable examples of some of the images, including both sizes of number 427, "Prof. Lowe reconnoitering at Battle of Fair Oaks and telegraphing to McClellan's headquarters." A comparison of the two sizes clearly shows how a cropped version of the album card image was used on the carte de visite, but the same size paper text label used on both.
  - Image numbers 102-646, not inclusive (Offsite-box 8, Folder unknown container)
- Series VI: Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the War
  Series VI holds random plates from that two-volume, 100-image album of views published after the war by Philp & Solomons (Washington: 1866). The publication consisted of albumen prints taken by Alexander Gardner during the war, which were mounted within a lithographed border on sheets with letterpress captions. The plates found here came from a variety of sources, and many have been cropped to various dimensions, possibly having to do with their exhibition history. The Society does hold a complete copy of the Sketch Book, located in the library collections, but does not have a complete set of loose plates. There are duplicates of many of the plates, and many of the images appear in Series I and III.
  Images are filed by plate number taken from the published volumes. This plate set is not complete.
  - Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the War: Plates 3-6 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 85)
    Scope and Contents
    Plate 3 - Fairfax Court-House
    Plate 4 - Stone Church, Centreville
    Plate 5 - Fortifications on Heights of Centreville
    Plate 6 - Quaker Guns, Centreville
  - Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the War: Plates 8-9 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 86)
    Plate 8 - Mathews House, Battle-field of Bull Run
    Plate 9 - Ruins at Manassas
  - Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the War: Plates 22-25 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 87)
    Plate 22 - Signal Tower, Elk Mountain, overlooking Battle-field of Antietam
    Plate 24 - Scene in Pleasant Valley, foot of South Mountain, Maryland
    Plate 25 - Pontoon Bridge, across the Potomac at Berlin
  - Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the War: Plates 33, 40 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 88)
    Plate 33 - Evacuation of Aquia Creek
    Plate 40 - A Sharpshooter's Last Sleep, on Battle-field of Gettysburg, July, 1863
  - Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the War: Plates 41, 44, 46 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 89)
    Plate 41 - Home of a Rebel Sharpshooter, Battle-field of Gettysburg, July, 1863
    Plate 44 - Slaughter Pen, foot of Round Top, Battle-field of Gettysburg
    Plate 46 - Provost Marshal's Office, Aquia Creek
  - Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the War: Plates 51-54, 56-58 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 90)
    Plate 51 - The "Shebang," or Quarters Sanitary Commission, Brandy Station
    Plate 52 - Residence of Quartermaster Third Army Corps
    Plate 53 - Headquarters Christian Commission, in the Field
    Plate 54 - Field Hospital, Second Army Corps Brandy Station
    Plate 56 - Headquarters New York Herald, in the Field
    Plate 57 - Camp Architecture
    Plate 58 - Pontoon Boat
  - Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the War: Plates 61-62, 67-68 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 91)
    Plate 61 - Commissary Department, Headquarters Army of the Potomac
    Plate 62 - U.S. Military Telegraph Construction Corps.
    Plate 67 - Quarles' Mills, on the North Anna
    Plate 68 - Charles City Court-House
  - Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the War: Plates 73-74, 77, 80 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 92)
    Plate 73 - U.S. Military Telegraph Battery Wagon
    Plate 74 - Poplar Grove Church, built by the 50th N.Y.V. Engineers
    Plate 77 - Army Forge Scene
    Plate 80 - Johnson's Mill, near Petersburg
  - Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the War: Plates 81-89 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 93)
    Plate 81 - View of Gas Works, Petersburg, showing effects of bombardment
    Plate 82 - View on the Appomattox, near Campbell's Bridge
    Plate 83 - Quarters of Men in Fort Sedgwick, generally known as Fort Hell